# **Diane Akasike**

Irvington, NJ | 862-279-1457 dianeakasike@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/diane-akasike

Self-motivated and passionate entry-level web developer and designer with 5+ years of experience in customer service and 2 years of experience in Information Technology. Solution-oriented, excellent communicator who pays close attention to detail, has strong work ethic, and experience working on teams. Desire to drive business impact in a constantly accelerating workplace. Willing to relocate anywhere within the US.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATION**

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Information Technology, Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ (GPA: 3.4) CompTIA ITF+ (Information Technology Fundamentals) Certification

Sep 2017 - May 2021

Semester: Fall 2019

Semester: Spring 2021

Oct 2020

#### **BASIC TECHNICAL SKILLS**

√ Object-Oriented Programming Web Design √ Hypertext Markup Language (HTML5) Website Development/Maintenance ✓ Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) Python 3 ✓ Communication Agile Software Development Java

#### RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Website Technician Sep 2020 - May 2021

Rutgers School of Arts and Sciences (SAS) Dean's Office - Computer Operations: New Brunswick, NJ

- Website Maintenance Manage and maintain 100+ Rutgers SAS websites using Joomla Content Management System by working closely with a small team of web developers to increase the number of hits to the websites and generate revenue for SAS IT Web services
  - Quality Assurance Inspect 50+ websites for broken links, error messages blank pages, and uneven formatting to improve website quality and user experience
  - o Troubleshooting Monitor incoming requests from school departments via an online work order system, decreasing wait times for clients to receive responses and assistance
  - o Security Test front and back end of websites after software updates for security vulnerabilities to ensure website performance was not inhibited and website administrators are able to successfully login
- Communication Converse with clients via workorder system and team members via Slack to understand clients' requests for updating webpages
  - o Client Satisfaction Have completed and received positive feedback from clients and/or team members for 100% of the requests assigned to me
- HTML5 Inspect and modify code to troubleshoot formatting and page layout issues or to efficiently revise repetitive content on SAS websites

Web Developer (Remote) Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Bridgeport Youth Lacrosse (BYL): Bridgeport, CT

- Web Design Organized page structure and content by use of development tools as specified by BYL according to their needs and make suggestions to improve user experience and functionality of the website
- Website Development Reconstructed current, incomplete website by creating the design and layout of 10+ web pages and updating or removing outdated information from existing content to meet client needs
  - WordPress Implemented eCommerce functionality into existing website to meet client's marketing needs using WooCommerce
  - o Google Cloud Developed a Web App to generate outgoing emails from online store to troubleshoot mail failure errors from WordPress
  - o Social Media Integration Integrated social media posts into feed on website homepage to increase user engagement and fulfill a key priority of the President of the BYL Program
  - o Optimization Optimized page load speeds, image sizes, and JavaScript and CSS delivery to improve bounce rates and search engine rankings
- Agile Software Development Utilized Jira software to track and organize agile software development process to maintain transparency with team
  - o Sprint Planning Estimated effort for requirements and sequence backlog issues into one-week sprints to define time-based deliverables
  - o Issue management Prioritized implementation of solutions to manage issues pointed out by user testing
  - Standup Meetings Participated in biweekly standup meetings with board director via Zoom to report project progress and issues
- Communication Collaborated with stakeholders and contributors from the Board of Directors, the BYL Program, and outside parties to understand the overall vision and end goal for the organization website
- HTML5/CSS Inspected and modified semantics and formatting with HTML5 and styling with CSS to fix issues with structuring and presenting content
- Security Develop and managed system of backing up HTML code to create a habit of maintaining cyber security best practices

#### RELEVANT PROJECTS

# • Introduction to Computer Concepts

- o Gained an understanding of basic mathematical-theoretical principles that govern the functioning of computers and the role of creative thinking and problem solving in building software applications
- o Collaborated with a group of five team members and used Java programming language to develop a conceptual solution to a designed problem

## • Object-Oriented Programming

- Semester: Spring 2020 o Introduced to principles of object-oriented analysis, design and programming and discovered interactive capabilities of 3rd-party public application programming interfaces
- o Utilized Python 3 programming language to extract data from Twitter's API in order to focus on developing creative thinking for analyzing a problem domain and designing a solution to resolve it

 Web Design Semester: Spring 2020

- o Studied the implications of web design in meeting organizational and client needs, and how to transform client requirements from sketch to wireframe to high-fidelity prototype
- o Built a basic online portfolio for myself using HTML5 and CSS to apply basic principles and techniques of web design

## • Independent Study

- o Designed and managed my own program of study based on my existing experience and knowledge as well as my long-term intentions
- o Created a professional portfolio website using Bootstrap Templates with HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript to showcase the relevant work I have completed in previous ITI courses, jobs, and outside training